Guide to the Time Inc. People Publishing and Business Records 1973-2003 MS 3009-RG 27
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Assistant Publisher Charlotte Schiff Jones Files, 1973-1978; 1.5 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  - Circulation Reports, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 11)
  - Conventions: California: September 23, 1977 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 12)
  - Durrell, Dick, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 13)
  - Fortune, 1977 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 14)
  - International Editions, 1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 15)
  - Legal, 1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 16)
  - Luncheons/Meetings, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 17)
  - Magazine Development, 1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 18)
  - Market Research, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 19)
  - Marketing: Fact Sheets, 1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 20)
  - Marketing: Focus Groups, 1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 22)
  - Merchandising (Shopper), 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 23)
  - People: Covers For Merchandising Purposes, 1974-1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 24-26)
  - Photo Show, 1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 27)
  - Posters, 1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 28)
  - Promotion, 1977 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 29)
  - Promotion Budget, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 30)
  - Publicity, 1973-1978 (Offsite-box 3041, Folder 31-32)
  - Sales Memos, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3042, Folder 1)
  - Starch Reports, 1977 (Offsite-box 3042, Folder 2)
  - Steer Meetings, 1978 (Offsite-box 3042, Folder 3)
  - Television: Dinah!, 1978 (Offsite-box 3042, Folder 4)
  - Television Special Edition: Developmental Ideas, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3042, Folder 5)
  - Time Distribution Service (TDS), 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3042, Folder 6)
  - Weekly Reports, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3042, Folder 7-8)
  - Young And Rubicam, 1978 (Offsite-box 3042, Folder 9)
- Series III. Marketing Files, 1973-1998; 4 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
  Arranged into three subseries:
  Subseries III.A. General Marketing Files Subseries III.B. Associate Consumer Marketing Director John Hartig Files Subseries III.C. Assistant Consumer Marketing Director Hank Fifield Files
  - Subseries III.A. General Marketing Files, 1973-1978; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Materials range from when People magazine was under the Magazine Development Group to when People became its own department by 1978. Includes budgets, research reports, Magazine Development Group invoices, advertising information, and memoranda. Most materials originated from Malcolm Ochs, Marketing Director in the Magazine Development Group. Other notable persons include Chuck Lund, People Director of Marketing Services, and Dick Thomas, People Advertising Sales Director.
    Some files are similar to advertising information found in the Richard Durrell files.
    - Account Comparison Report, 1978 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 1-2)
    - Ad Pages, 1977 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 3)
    - Advertising Recall Study: November 10, 1977 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 4)
    - Agency Ranking Report, 1977 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 5)
    - Audience Compositions, 1977 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 6-7)
    - Audience Research, 1976 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 8)
    - Awareness And Tracking Study, 1976 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 9)
    - Beta Research, undated (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 10)
    - Budget, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 11-13)
    - Circulation Consultants, 1975 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 14)
    - Circulation Research, 1976 (Offsite-box 3049, Folder 15)
    - College Penetration (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 1)
    - Cover Testing, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 2-3)
    - Focus Groups, 1976 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 4-5)
    - Frequency of Reading Study, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 6)
    - Gardner, Lou, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 7)
    - Jennings, Donny, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 8)
    - Marketing Development Group Invoices, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 9)
    - Marketing and Promotion Budget, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 10)
    - People Circulation, 1974-1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 11)
    - People International, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 12)
    - People versus National Enquirer, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 13)
    - People Primary: Total Audience Composition Tables: Adults (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 14)
    - People Primary: Total Audience Composition Tables: Education (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 15)
    - People Primary: Total Audience Composition Tables: Men/Women (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 16)
    - People/Us Study, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 17)
    - Power Robertson & Company, 1975 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 18)
    - Research, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 19)
    - Standard Rate and Data Service, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 20)
    - Target Group Index, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 21-22)
    - Time Inc. Audience Studies, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 23)
    - Telegraf Dispatch, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 24)
    - Valu-Tape, 1977 (Offsite-box 3050, Folder 25)
  - Subseries III.B. Associate Consumer Marketing Director John Hartig Files, 1979-1997; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    John Hartig was Associate Consumer Marketing Director at People magazine, who had responsibility for circulation and development, from 1991 to 1993. In 1993, he transitioned to the InStyle magazine launch team as director of consumer marketing and development. He had joined Time Inc. in 1985 as an Ad Sales Manager for People.
    Materials includes: poll results from marketing company Pulse On America, Nielsen demographics numbers, 1990 Census results, and 1993 Newsstand Task Force materials. The test and launch materials for InStyle magazine are from after Hartig left People in 1994 to join InStyle.
    The folder with People magazine Five Year Plans 1978-1983 contains memoranda from Susan Ferris, Marketing Director, Publishing Division of Magazine Development.
    - 1990 Census Tape File 3 Summary (Offsite-box 3044, Folder 2-3)
    - Five Year Plan: 1978-1982, 1979-1983, 1979-1986 (Offsite-box 3044, Folder 4)
    - InStyle Test/Launch, 1995 (Offsite-box 3044, Folder 5-7)
    - Newsstand Task Force, 1993-1994 (Offsite-box 3044, Folder 8-11)
    - Nielsen National Audience Demographics, 1994 (Offsite-box 3044, Folder 12)
    - Pulse On America Polls, 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 3044, Folder 13-15)
  - Subseries III.C. Assistant Consumer Marketing Director Hank Fifield Files, 1989-1998; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Hank Fifield was Assistant Consumer Marketing Director at People magazine, where he focused on working with other departments to appeal to buyers. Before holding this role, Fifield was Director of Retail Sales at People.
    Citation:
    Hooper, Bill. Email to Melanie Rinehart, 7 April 2019.
    Materials include budgets, sales analysis, copies of books, memoranda, copies of People magazine, and materials relating to the Jerry Garcia and Selena memorial editions of People.
    - 1995 Best and Worst Dressed (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 1)
    - 1995 Celebrity Weddings (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 2)
    - Budget and Analysis, 1996-1998 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 3-4)
    - Budget and Strategic Plan, 1994 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 5-6)
    - Business Plans That Win Venture Capital by Terrence McGarty, 1989 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 7)
    - Celebrity Weddings, 1993-1995 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 8-9)
    - Convenience Store News, 1996 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 11)
    - Distribution Study of Grocery Store Sales, 1993 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 12)
    - DYG Scan Trend Identification Program, 1992 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 13)
    - Focus Report Writing, 1993 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 14)
    - Jerry Garcia Tribute, 1995 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1993-1996 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 16)
    - Old Theme Memoranda, 1993-1994 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 17)
    - Selena Coverage, 1995 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 18)
    - Third Quarter RDP, 1996 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 19)
    - Wholesaler Incentive Plan, 1997 (Offsite-box 3116, Folder 20)
- Series IV. Advertising Files, 1975-1977; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Includes records from the Publisher's Information Bureau, which tracked magazine advertising paging, expenditures and related information for companies advertising within People. Also included are statistical computer anaylses on sales and demographics numbers. The person who originally collected or created these files is unknown.
  Similar files can be found in the Richard Durrell files, though some are empty folders. Similar material in this series may have originally belonged to Durrell.
  - Benchmark Optimization, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3043, Folder 1)
  - Cranks, QStats, And QRF Analysis, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3043, Folder 2-10)
  - Focus Groups: New Jersey: December, 1977 (Offsite-box 3043, Folder 11)
  - People Advertising Record, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3043, Folder 12-14)
  - Publisher's Information Bureau Advertising Records, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3043, Folder 15)
  - Starch Analysis: October 24, 1977 (Offsite-box 3043, Folder 16)
  - Tapper IRF Analysis, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3044, Folder 1)
- Series V. Public Affairs Records, 1977-1995; 16.1 Linear feet in 17 record cartons
  The majority of records are press releases sent out by various people within People Public Affairs regarding upcoming articles and staff updates. The press releases may be accompanied by materials such as memoranda, news clippings, photographs, and copies of People magazine. Also includes publicity materials from the Public Affairs Director's office on cover stories.
  Arranged into four subseries:
  Subseries VI.A. Public Affairs Director Susan Ollinick Files
  Subseries VI.B. Publicity Manager Press Releases
  Subseries VI.C. Trade Publicity Manager Elizabeth Wagner Files
  Subseries VI.D. Press Releases On Staff
  - Subseries VI.A. Public Affairs Director Susan Ollinick Files, 1995; 1.6 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
    Includes publicity materials for all People magazine issues and special editions from 1995, when Susan Ollinick held the role of Public Affairs Director, such as press releases, arrangements for on-air interviews with Susan Ollinick regarding People stories, memoranda, and FedEx receipts and fax cover sheets to show who press releases were being sent to. Some of publicity coordinator Akieva Harrell's materials are also included. For some issues a chart with each article and its author and editor are included.
    Folders are titled with the issue's cover article and release date.
    Notably includes coverage of the Selena and Jerry Garcia special memorial editions.
    Chronological by week.
    - Issue Publicity, 1995 January 9-April 3 (Offsite-box 3076, Folder 23-34)
    - Issue Publicity, 1995 April 3-September 11 (Offsite-box 3077)
    - Issue Publicity, 1995 September 18-November 27 (Offsite-box 3078, Folder 1-13)
    - Issue Publicity [RESTRICTED], 1995 February-May (Offsite-box R43)
  - Subseries VI.B. Publicity Manager Press Releases, 1980-1988; 6 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
    This subseries includes covers when Penelope Karageorge and Elizabeth "Betsy" Wagner each held the title of Publicity Manager. Penelope Karageorge held the role from 1980 to 1985, and Elizabeth Wagner held the role from 1985 to approximately 1994.
    Subseries includes editorial press releases about People magazine featured cover stories, studies, and events hosted by People, including photographic exhibitions.
    Chronological.
    - Issue Edit Press Releases, 1980-1983 (Offsite-box 3067)
    - Issue Edit Press Releases, 1983-1986 (Offsite-box 3068)
    - Issue Edit Press Releases, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 3069)
    - Issue Edit Press Releases, 1987 (Offsite-box 3070)
    - Issue Edit Press Releases, 1988 (Offsite-box 3071)
    - Issue Edit Press Releases, 1988 (Offsite-box 3072)
  - Subseries VI.C. Trade Publicity Manager Elizabeth Wagner Files, 1983-1988; 6 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
    These materials are from when Elizabeth "Betsy" Wagner held the role of Trade Publicity Manager. Includes press releases and other materials related to People magazine's advertising trade publicity, concerning specific advertising campaigns run in the magazine. Also includes photographs and photographic negatives of People magazine sponsered events and staff used for publicity and internal staff updates. The original box was labeled for the A-D range and indicates this is not the full range of files at present.
    Notable is the coverage of Ten: The Musical, a People produced 1984 musical about the first decade of the magazine. Scripts, songbooks, cast lists, guests lists, and press releases regarding Ten: The Musical are included.
    Press release titles reflect the name of the advertiser or the event title.
    Alphabetical by event title, last name, or title of press release.
    - "Active People" Photo Show College Tour, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 1-2)
    - Baja Club Party, 1987 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 3)
    - Bears Party: 7 October, 1986 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 4)
    - Bright Lights Screening: 29 March, 1988 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 15)
    - Boomer Photo Contest Winner, 1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 5)
    - Boomer Seminar Photos: 8 March, 1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 6-7)
    - Boomer Seminar: Chicago: 5 June, 1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 8-9)
    - Boomer Seminar: Detroit: 3 June, 1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 10)
    - Boomer Seminar: Los Angeles, 1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 11)
    - Boston Photo Show, 1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 12-13)
    - Buster Poindexter, Roseland: 29 February, 1988 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 15)
    - Campbell's Photos, 1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 16)
    - Catherine Barron-Heiskell Award, 1986 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 17)
    - Central Park, 1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 18)
    - Consumer Electronics Show Breakfast: 13 August, 1986 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 19)
    - Consumer Electronics Show: Las Vegas: January, 1986 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 20)
    - Consumer Electronics Show/People Party: January, 1988 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 21)
    - Consumer Electronics Show Seminar Photos: 31 January, 1985 (Offsite-box 3094, Folder 22-23)
    - Consumer Electronics Show Seminar Photos: 9 September, 1985 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 1)
    - Consumer Electronics Show Photos: Las Vegas: 10 January, 1987 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 2)
    - Consumer Electronics Show Photos: Top 10 Retailer of the Year: 7 January, 1984 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 3)
    - Dallas Photo Show: Photos/Contact Sheets: 22 January, 1986 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 4)
    - Dallas Sporting Goods Show, 1986 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 5)
    - D'Aloia, John, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 6-7)
    - Detroit Party: "People Performs", 1988 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 8)
    - Dezerland Party: Proctor and Gamble: 19 January, 1988 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 9)
    - Dodge Morgan Party: 16 September, 1986 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 10)
    - Dodge, Mark: Sales Manager, 1977 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 11)
    - Edit Luncheon Photos: 10 April, 1985 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 12)
    - Flynn, Dick, 1985 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 13)
    - Inter-office Photos, 1985 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 14-15)
    - People Magazine Sales Staff Pictures, 1977 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 16)
    - People Magazine Staff Photos, 1977 (Offsite-box 3095, Folder 17)
    - Trade Press Releases: A-C, 1983-1987 (Offsite-box 3073)
    - Trade Press Releases: C-H, 1984-1988 (Offsite-box 3074)
    - Trade Press Releases: H-T, 1984-1988 (Offsite-box 3075)
    - Trade Press Releases: T-Z, 1984-1987 (Offsite-box 3076, Folder 1-22)
  - Subseries VI.D. Press Releases On Staff, 1977-1990; 2.5 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    Records include press releases regarding staff and personnel changes in People's advertising and sales staff. Press releases may be accompanied by photographs, news clippings, and announcements sent directly to sales staff.
    Alphabetical by last name.
    - Staff Press Releases: Abram, Jane-Brower, Montgomery, 1977-1988 (Offsite-box 3078, Folder 14-38)
    - Staff Press Releases: Burch, Jeffrey-Lincoln, Victoria, 1977-1989 (Offsite-box 3079)
    - Staff Press Releases: Magee, Karen-Zappulla, Fran, 1981-1990 (Offsite-box 3080)
- Series VI. General Files, 1973-2003; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
  The General Files come from material waiting to be filed by the Time Inc. Archives. Records contains the contents of a hanging folder titled "People History" including copies of a 1973 prospectus and some memoranda and speeches from publisher Nora McAniff; and ephemera and audiovisual from the 25th anniversary.
  Organized alphabetically with arrangement imposed.
  - People History, 1973-2003 (Offsite-box 4185, Folder 1-2)
  - 25th Anniversary: Branded Planner, [1999] (Offsite-box 4185, Folder 3)
  - 25th Anniversary: Concert: "Carole King: Making Music with Friends", 1999 (Offsite-box 4185, Folder 4-5)
    Includes audiovisual material.
    1 videocassette (VHS) (7 min. 45 sec.): 1/2 in.